import '../../../models/question.dart';

final Map<String, List<Question>> computer10th = {
      "Unit 1": [
        Question(
          questionText: "The first step in problem-solving is:",
          options: ["Coding", "Testing", "Analyzing the problem", "Debugging"],
          correctAnswer: "Analyzing the problem",
          selectedClass: "10th",
          subject: "Computer",
          selectedUnit: "Unit 1",
        ),

        Question(
          questionText: "An algorithm is:",
          options: ["Program code", "Graphical representation", "Step-by-step procedure", "Error message"],
          correctAnswer: "Step-by-step procedure",
          selectedClass: "10th",
          subject: "Computer",
          selectedUnit: "Unit 1",
        ),

        Question(
          questionText: "Pseudocode is written in:",
          options: ["Binary code", "Flowchart symbols", "Simple English-like statements", "Mathematical formulas"],
          correctAnswer: "Simple English-like statements",
          selectedClass: "10th",
          subject: "Computer",
          selectedUnit: "Unit 1",
        ),

        Question(
          questionText: "Flowchart symbols for start/stop are:",
          options: ["Rectangle", "Diamond", "Oval", "Parallelogram"],
          correctAnswer: "Oval",
          selectedClass: "10th",
          subject: "Computer",
          selectedUnit: "Unit 1",
        ),

        Question(
          questionText: "Flowchart symbol for input/output is:",
          options: ["Oval", "Rectangle", "Parallelogram", "Diamond"],
          correctAnswer: "Parallelogram",
          selectedClass: "10th",
          subject: "Computer",
          selectedUnit: "Unit 1",
        ),

        Question(
          questionText: "Flowchart symbol for decision is:",
          options: ["Oval", "Diamond", "Rectangle", "Circle"],
          correctAnswer: "Diamond",
          selectedClass: "10th",
          subject: "Computer",
          selectedUnit: "Unit 1",
        ),

        Question(
          questionText: "Machine language consists of:",
          options: ["Binary digits", "Mnemonics", "English-like commands", "Flowchart symbols"],
          correctAnswer: "Binary digits",
          selectedClass: "10th",
          subject: "Computer",
          selectedUnit: "Unit 1",
        ),

        Question(
          questionText: "Assembly language uses:",
          options: ["Binary codes", "Mnemonics", "English words", "Flowchart diagrams"],
          correctAnswer: "Mnemonics",
          selectedClass: "10th",
          subject: "Computer",
          selectedUnit: "Unit 1",
        ),

        Question(
          questionText: "Which translator converts assembly into machine code?",
          options: ["Compiler", "Assembler", "Interpreter", "Debugger"],
          correctAnswer: "Assembler",
          selectedClass: "10th",
          subject: "Computer",
          selectedUnit: "Unit 1",
        ),

        Question(
          questionText: "A compiler translates:",
          options: ["Whole program at once", "Line by line", "Only flowcharts", "Only pseudocode"],
          correctAnswer: "Whole program at once",
          selectedClass: "10th",
          subject: "Computer",
          selectedUnit: "Unit 1",
        ),

        Question(
          questionText: "An interpreter translates:",
          options: ["Whole program", "Line by line", "Only flowcharts", "Only binary"],
          correctAnswer: "Line by line",
          selectedClass: "10th",
          subject: "Computer",
          selectedUnit: "Unit 1",
        ),

        Question(
          questionText: "C++ was developed by:",
          options: ["Dennis Ritchie", "Charles Babbage", "Bjarne Stroustrup", "James Gosling"],
          correctAnswer: "Bjarne Stroustrup",
          selectedClass: "10th",
          subject: "Computer",
          selectedUnit: "Unit 1",
        ),

        Question(
          questionText: "C++ was developed in:",
          options: ["1969", "1979", "1985", "1995"],
          correctAnswer: "1979",
          selectedClass: "10th",
          subject: "Computer",
          selectedUnit: "Unit 1",
        ),

        Question(
          questionText: "Which of the following is a high-level language?",
          options: ["Binary", "Assembly", "C++", "Hexadecimal"],
          correctAnswer: "C++",
          selectedClass: "10th",
          subject: "Computer",
          selectedUnit: "Unit 1",
        ),

        Question(
          questionText: "Which of the following is a low-level language?",
          options: ["C++", "Python", "Assembly", "Java"],
          correctAnswer: "Assembly",
          selectedClass: "10th",
          subject: "Computer",
          selectedUnit: "Unit 1",
        ),

        Question(
          questionText: "Errors in program syntax are called:",
          options: ["Logical errors", "Syntax errors", "Runtime errors", "System errors"],
          correctAnswer: "Syntax errors",
          selectedClass: "10th",
          subject: "Computer",
          selectedUnit: "Unit 1",
        ),

        Question(
          questionText: "Errors that give wrong results but no error messages are:",
          options: ["Syntax errors", "Logical errors", "Runtime errors", "Debug errors"],
          correctAnswer: "Logical errors",
          selectedClass: "10th",
          subject: "Computer",
          selectedUnit: "Unit 1",
        ),

        Question(
          questionText: "Which error occurs during program execution?",
          options: ["Syntax error", "Logical error", "Runtime error", "Semantic error"],
          correctAnswer: "Runtime error",
          selectedClass: "10th",
          subject: "Computer",
          selectedUnit: "Unit 1",
        ),

        Question(
          questionText: "Debugging means:",
          options: ["Finding and fixing errors", "Designing flowcharts", "Writing pseudocode", "Compiling program"],
          correctAnswer: "Finding and fixing errors",
          selectedClass: "10th",
          subject: "Computer",
          selectedUnit: "Unit 1",
        ),

        Question(
          questionText: "Which of the following is not a translator?",
          options: ["Compiler", "Interpreter", "Assembler", "Debugger"],
          correctAnswer: "Debugger",
          selectedClass: "10th",
          subject: "Computer",
          selectedUnit: "Unit 1",
        ),

        //Short Questions
        Question(
          questionText: "Define programming.",
          answer: "Programming is the process of writing instructions for a computer to solve a problem.",
          selectedClass: "10th",
          subject: "Computer",
          selectedUnit: "Unit 1",
        ),

        Question(
          questionText: "What is a program?",
          answer: "A program is a set of instructions written in a programming language to perform a specific task.",
          selectedClass: "10th",
          subject: "Computer",
          selectedUnit: "Unit 1",
        ),

        Question(
          questionText: "What is problem-solving in computer science?",
          answer: "Problem-solving is the process of identifying a problem and developing a step-by-step solution to solve it.",
          selectedClass: "10th",
          subject: "Computer",
          selectedUnit: "Unit 1",
        ),

        Question(
          questionText: "What is an algorithm?",
          answer: "An algorithm is a finite sequence of steps to solve a problem.",
          selectedClass: "10th",
          subject: "Computer",
          selectedUnit: "Unit 1",
        ),

        Question(
          questionText: "Define pseudocode.",
          answer: "Pseudocode is a simple way of writing algorithms in plain English statements that resemble programming structure.",
          selectedClass: "10th",
          subject: "Computer",
          selectedUnit: "Unit 1",
        ),

        Question(
          questionText: "What is a flowchart?",
          answer: "A flowchart is a graphical representation of an algorithm using symbols.",
          selectedClass: "10th",
          subject: "Computer",
          selectedUnit: "Unit 1",
        ),

        Question(
          questionText: "Which symbol is used for start and stop in a flowchart?",
          answer: "An oval (ellipse) is used for start and stop.",
          selectedClass: "10th",
          subject: "Computer",
          selectedUnit: "Unit 1",
        ),

        Question(
          questionText: "Which symbol represents input/output in a flowchart?",
          answer: "A parallelogram is used for input/output in flowcharts.",
          selectedClass: "10th",
          subject: "Computer",
          selectedUnit: "Unit 1",
        ),

        Question(
          questionText: "Which symbol represents a process in a flowchart?",
          answer: "A rectangle is used for processing steps in a flowchart.",
          selectedClass: "10th",
          subject: "Computer",
          selectedUnit: "Unit 1",
        ),

        Question(
          questionText: "Which symbol is used for decision-making in a flowchart?",
          answer: "A diamond is used for decision-making.",
          selectedClass: "10th",
          subject: "Computer",
          selectedUnit: "Unit 1",
        ),

        Question(
          questionText: "What is machine language?",
          answer: "Machine language is the lowest-level programming language consisting of binary digits (0s and 1s).",
          selectedClass: "10th",
          subject: "Computer",
          selectedUnit: "Unit 1",
        ),

        Question(
          questionText: "Why is machine language difficult for humans?",
          answer: "Because it uses only 0s and 1s, which are hard for humans to read and debug.",
          selectedClass: "10th",
          subject: "Computer",
          selectedUnit: "Unit 1",
        ),

        Question(
          questionText: "Define assembly language.",
          answer: "Assembly language uses mnemonic codes instead of binary to represent instructions.",
          selectedClass: "10th",
          subject: "Computer",
          selectedUnit: "Unit 1",
        ),

        Question(
          questionText: "What is the role of an assembler?",
          answer: "An assembler translates assembly language programs into machine language.",
          selectedClass: "10th",
          subject: "Computer",
          selectedUnit: "Unit 1",
        ),

        Question(
          questionText: "What are high-level languages?",
          answer: "High-level languages are easy-to-use languages that use English-like instructions, e.g., C++, Java, Python.",
          selectedClass: "10th",
          subject: "Computer",
          selectedUnit: "Unit 1",
        ),

        Question(
          questionText: "What is a compiler?",
          answer: "A compiler is a translator that converts a whole program into machine language at once.",
          selectedClass: "10th",
          subject: "Computer",
          selectedUnit: "Unit 1",
        ),

        Question(
          questionText: "What is an interpreter?",
          answer: "An interpreter translates and executes code line by line.",
          selectedClass: "10th",
          subject: "Computer",
          selectedUnit: "Unit 1",
        ),

        Question(
          questionText: "Differentiate between compiler and interpreter.",
          answer: "A compiler translates the entire program at once, while an interpreter translates and executes line by line.",
          selectedClass: "10th",
          subject: "Computer",
          selectedUnit: "Unit 1",
        ),

        Question(
          questionText: "What is C++?",
          answer: "C++ is a high-level, object-oriented programming language developed by Bjarne Stroustrup.",
          selectedClass: "10th",
          subject: "Computer",
          selectedUnit: "Unit 1",
        ),

        Question(
          questionText: "Who developed C++ and when?",
          answer: "Bjarne Stroustrup developed C++ in 1979 at Bell Laboratories.",
          selectedClass: "10th",
          subject: "Computer",
          selectedUnit: "Unit 1",
        ),

        Question(
          questionText: "What is meant by problem analysis?",
          answer: "Problem analysis is the process of understanding a problem before writing an algorithm or program.",
          selectedClass: "10th",
          subject: "Computer",
          selectedUnit: "Unit 1",
        ),

        Question(
          questionText: "Why is algorithm design important?",
          answer: "It helps reduce errors and provides a clear roadmap before coding.",
          selectedClass: "10th",
          subject: "Computer",
          selectedUnit: "Unit 1",
        ),

        Question(
          questionText: "Give an example of a simple algorithm.",
          answer: "Algorithm for finding the sum of two numbers: Step 1: Input A and B. Step 2: Add A and B. Step 3: Display result.",
          selectedClass: "10th",
          subject: "Computer",
          selectedUnit: "Unit 1",
        ),

        Question(
          questionText: "Write pseudocode for adding two numbers.",
          answer: "Input A, B → Sum = A + B → Print Sum.",
          selectedClass: "10th",
          subject: "Computer",
          selectedUnit: "Unit 1",
        ),

        Question(
          questionText: "Write a simple C++ program to display 'Hello World'.",
          answer: "#include <iostream> \nusing namespace std; \nint main(){ \n cout << \"Hello World\"; \n return 0; \n}",
          selectedClass: "10th",
          subject: "Computer",
          selectedUnit: "Unit 1",
        ),

        Question(
          questionText: "What is debugging?",
          answer: "Debugging is the process of finding and fixing errors in a program.",
          selectedClass: "10th",
          subject: "Computer",
          selectedUnit: "Unit 1",
        ),

        Question(
          questionText: "What is syntax error?",
          answer: "Errors that occur when rules of a programming language are violated.",
          selectedClass: "10th",
          subject: "Computer",
          selectedUnit: "Unit 1",
        ),

        Question(
          questionText: "What is logical error?",
          answer: "An error in the program’s logic that gives wrong results but no error message.",
          selectedClass: "10th",
          subject: "Computer",
          selectedUnit: "Unit 1",
        ),

        Question(
          questionText: "What is run-time error?",
          answer: "An error that occurs during execution, such as dividing a number by zero.",
          selectedClass: "10th",
          subject: "Computer",
          selectedUnit: "Unit 1",
        ),
      ],
  "Unit 2": [
    // MCQS
    Question(
      questionText: "Which function is used to display output in C?",
      options: ["print()", "echo()", "printf()", "display()"],
      correctAnswer: "printf()",
      selectedClass: "10th",
      subject: "Computer",
      selectedUnit: "Unit 2",
    ),

    Question(
      questionText: "Which function is used to take input in C?",
      options: ["scanf()", "cin>>", "input()", "read()"],
      correctAnswer: "scanf()",
      selectedClass: "10th",
      subject: "Computer",
      selectedUnit: "Unit 2",
    ),

    Question(
      questionText: "Which format specifier is used for integers?",
      options: ["%c", "%d", "%s", "%f"],
      correctAnswer: "%d",
      selectedClass: "10th",
      subject: "Computer",
      selectedUnit: "Unit 2",
    ),

    Question(
      questionText: "Which format specifier is used for floating-point values?",
      options: ["%f", "%d", "%s", "%c"],
      correctAnswer: "%f",
      selectedClass: "10th",
      subject: "Computer",
      selectedUnit: "Unit 2",
    ),

    Question(
      questionText: "Which format specifier is used for characters?",
      options: ["%d", "%c", "%s", "%f"],
      correctAnswer: "%c",
      selectedClass: "10th",
      subject: "Computer",
      selectedUnit: "Unit 2",
    ),

    Question(
      questionText: "Which symbol is used before variable name in scanf?",
      options: ["+", "&", "*", "#"],
      correctAnswer: "&",
      selectedClass: "10th",
      subject: "Computer",
      selectedUnit: "Unit 2",
    ),

    Question(
      questionText: "Escape sequence \\n is used for:",
      options: ["newline", "tab", "backspace", "null"],
      correctAnswer: "newline",
      selectedClass: "10th",
      subject: "Computer",
      selectedUnit: "Unit 2",
    ),

    Question(
      questionText: "Escape sequence \\t is used for:",
      options: ["tab", "newline", "backspace", "return"],
      correctAnswer: "tab",
      selectedClass: "10th",
      subject: "Computer",
      selectedUnit: "Unit 2",
    ),

    Question(
      questionText: "In C, strings are stored as:",
      options: ["Array of chars", "Single char", "Integer array", "Float array"],
      correctAnswer: "Array of chars",
      selectedClass: "10th",
      subject: "Computer",
      selectedUnit: "Unit 2",
    ),

    Question(
      questionText: "The format specifier %s is used for:",
      options: ["String", "Character", "Integer", "Float"],
      correctAnswer: "String",
      selectedClass: "10th",
      subject: "Computer",
      selectedUnit: "Unit 2",
    ),
    //Short Questions
    Question(
      questionText: "Which function is used to display output in C?",
      answer: "The printf() function.",
      selectedClass: "10th",
      subject: "Computer",
      selectedUnit: "Unit 2",
    ),

    Question(
      questionText: "Which function is used to take input in C?",
      answer: "The scanf() function.",
      selectedClass: "10th",
      subject: "Computer",
      selectedUnit: "Unit 2",
    ),

    Question(
      questionText: "What is a format specifier?",
      answer: "A symbol used in printf and scanf to specify the data type, such as %d for integers.",
      selectedClass: "10th",
      subject: "Computer",
      selectedUnit: "Unit 2",
    ),

    Question(
      questionText: "Which format specifier is used for integer values?",
      answer: "%d",
      selectedClass: "10th",
      subject: "Computer",
      selectedUnit: "Unit 2",
    ),

    Question(
      questionText: "Which format specifier is used for float values?",
      answer: "%f",
      selectedClass: "10th",
      subject: "Computer",
      selectedUnit: "Unit 2",
    ),

    Question(
      questionText: "Which format specifier is used for character values?",
      answer: "%c",
      selectedClass: "10th",
      subject: "Computer",
      selectedUnit: "Unit 2",
    ),

    Question(
      questionText: "Which format specifier is used for string values?",
      answer: "%s",
      selectedClass: "10th",
      subject: "Computer",
      selectedUnit: "Unit 2",
    ),

    Question(
      questionText: "What is the purpose of escape sequences?",
      answer: "Escape sequences are used to format output, e.g., \\n for newline, \\t for tab.",
      selectedClass: "10th",
      subject: "Computer",
      selectedUnit: "Unit 2",
    ),

    Question(
      questionText: "Write the statement to print 'Hello World' in C.",
      answer: "printf(\"Hello World\");",
      selectedClass: "10th",
      subject: "Computer",
      selectedUnit: "Unit 2",
    ),

    Question(
      questionText: "Write a statement to print a number stored in variable x.",
      answer: "printf(\"%d\", x);",
      selectedClass: "10th",
      subject: "Computer",
      selectedUnit: "Unit 2",
    ),

    Question(
      questionText: "Write a statement to input an integer in variable age.",
      answer: "scanf(\"%d\", &age);",
      selectedClass: "10th",
      subject: "Computer",
      selectedUnit: "Unit 2",
    ),

    Question(
      questionText: "Why do we use the '&' sign in scanf?",
      answer: "Because scanf requires the memory address of the variable.",
      selectedClass: "10th",
      subject: "Computer",
      selectedUnit: "Unit 2",
    ),

    Question(
      questionText: "Write a program to input two numbers and display their sum.",
      answer: "#include <stdio.h>\nint main(){int a,b;scanf(\"%d%d\",&a,&b);printf(\"%d\",a+b);return 0;}",
      selectedClass: "10th",
      subject: "Computer",
      selectedUnit: "Unit 2",
    ),

    Question(
      questionText: "Write the difference between printf and scanf.",
      answer: "printf is used for output, scanf is used for input.",
      selectedClass: "10th",
      subject: "Computer",
      selectedUnit: "Unit 2",
    ),

    Question(
      questionText: "What does the escape sequence \\n do?",
      answer: "It moves the cursor to the next line.",
      selectedClass: "10th",
      subject: "Computer",
      selectedUnit: "Unit 2",
    ),

    Question(
      questionText: "What does the escape sequence \\t do?",
      answer: "It inserts a tab space in output.",
      selectedClass: "10th",
      subject: "Computer",
      selectedUnit: "Unit 2",
    ),

    Question(
      questionText: "Write a statement that prints 'Pakistan' on two lines.",
      answer: "printf(\"Pak\\nistan\");",
      selectedClass: "10th",
      subject: "Computer",
      selectedUnit: "Unit 2",
    ),

    Question(
      questionText: "What is the general syntax of printf?",
      answer: "printf(\"format specifier\", variables);",
      selectedClass: "10th",
      subject: "Computer",
      selectedUnit: "Unit 2",
    ),

    Question(
      questionText: "What is the general syntax of scanf?",
      answer: "scanf(\"format specifier\", &variables);",
      selectedClass: "10th",
      subject: "Computer",
      selectedUnit: "Unit 2",
    ),

    Question(
      questionText: "Write a program to input a name and print it.",
      answer: "#include <stdio.h>\nint main(){char name[20];scanf(\"%s\",name);printf(\"%s\",name);return 0;}",
      selectedClass: "10th",
      subject: "Computer",
      selectedUnit: "Unit 2",
    ),

  ],
  "Unit 3": [
    //MCQs
    Question(
      questionText: "Which statement is used for decision making in C?",
      options: ["switch", "if", "for", "goto"],
      correctAnswer: "if",
      selectedClass: "10th",
      subject: "Computer",
      selectedUnit: "Unit 3",
    ),

    Question(
      questionText: "Which symbol is used for equality comparison?",
      options: ["=", "==", "!=", ">="],
      correctAnswer: "==",
      selectedClass: "10th",
      subject: "Computer",
      selectedUnit: "Unit 3",
    ),

    Question(
      questionText: "Which operator represents logical AND?",
      options: ["&&", "||", "!", "&"],
      correctAnswer: "&&",
      selectedClass: "10th",
      subject: "Computer",
      selectedUnit: "Unit 3",
    ),

    Question(
      questionText: "Which operator represents logical OR?",
      options: ["||", "&&", "!", "|"],
      correctAnswer: "||",
      selectedClass: "10th",
      subject: "Computer",
      selectedUnit: "Unit 3",
    ),

    Question(
      questionText: "Which operator represents logical NOT?",
      options: ["~", "!", "||", "&&"],
      correctAnswer: "!",
      selectedClass: "10th",
      subject: "Computer",
      selectedUnit: "Unit 3",
    ),

    Question(
      questionText: "What will be the result of (5 > 3 && 4 < 2)?",
      options: ["true", "false", "error", "0"],
      correctAnswer: "false",
      selectedClass: "10th",
      subject: "Computer",
      selectedUnit: "Unit 3",
    ),

    Question(
      questionText: "What is the output of if(2==2) printf(\"Equal\");?",
      options: ["2", "Equal", "Error", "True"],
      correctAnswer: "Equal",
      selectedClass: "10th",
      subject: "Computer",
      selectedUnit: "Unit 3",
    ),

    Question(
      questionText: "Which relational operator checks 'not equal'?",
      options: ["=", "==", "!=", "<>"],
      correctAnswer: "!=",
      selectedClass: "10th",
      subject: "Computer",
      selectedUnit: "Unit 3",
    ),

    Question(
      questionText: "Which of the following is a valid if statement?",
      options: ["if a>5", "if(a>5)", "if{a>5}", "if[a>5]"],
      correctAnswer: "if(a>5)",
      selectedClass: "10th",
      subject: "Computer",
      selectedUnit: "Unit 3",
    ),

    Question(
      questionText: "What will be the output of if(5<2) printf(\"Yes\"); else printf(\"No\");?",
      options: ["Yes", "No", "Error", "None"],
      correctAnswer: "No",
      selectedClass: "10th",
      subject: "Computer",
      selectedUnit: "Unit 3",
    ),

    //Short Questions

    Question(
      questionText: "What is conditional logic in C?",
      answer: "Conditional logic allows the program to take decisions based on conditions using statements like if and if-else.",
      selectedClass: "10th",
      subject: "Computer",
      selectedUnit: "Unit 3",
    ),

    Question(
      questionText: "Which statement is used for decision making in C?",
      answer: "The if statement.",
      selectedClass: "10th",
      subject: "Computer",
      selectedUnit: "Unit 3",
    ),

    Question(
      questionText: "What is the general syntax of if statement?",
      answer: "if(condition){\n   //statements\n}",
      selectedClass: "10th",
      subject: "Computer",
      selectedUnit: "Unit 3",
    ),

    Question(
      questionText: "What is the difference between if and if-else?",
      answer: "if checks a condition and executes code if true, while if-else executes one block if condition is true and another if false.",
      selectedClass: "10th",
      subject: "Computer",
      selectedUnit: "Unit 3",
    ),

    Question(
      questionText: "What is nested if?",
      answer: "When an if statement is written inside another if statement.",
      selectedClass: "10th",
      subject: "Computer",
      selectedUnit: "Unit 3",
    ),

    Question(
      questionText: "Write a relational operator that checks equality.",
      answer: "==",
      selectedClass: "10th",
      subject: "Computer",
      selectedUnit: "Unit 3",
    ),

    Question(
      questionText: "Which relational operator checks not equal?",
      answer: "!=",
      selectedClass: "10th",
      subject: "Computer",
      selectedUnit: "Unit 3",
    ),

    Question(
      questionText: "Which logical operator is used for AND?",
      answer: "&&",
      selectedClass: "10th",
      subject: "Computer",
      selectedUnit: "Unit 3",
    ),

    Question(
      questionText: "Which logical operator is used for OR?",
      answer: "||",
      selectedClass: "10th",
      subject: "Computer",
      selectedUnit: "Unit 3",
    ),

    Question(
      questionText: "Which logical operator is used for NOT?",
      answer: "!",
      selectedClass: "10th",
      subject: "Computer",
      selectedUnit: "Unit 3",
    ),

    Question(
      questionText: "Write a program to check whether a number is positive.",
      answer: "#include <stdio.h>\nint main(){int n;scanf(\"%d\",&n);if(n>0)printf(\"Positive\");return 0;}",
      selectedClass: "10th",
      subject: "Computer",
      selectedUnit: "Unit 3",
    ),

    Question(
      questionText: "Write a program to check whether a number is even or odd.",
      answer: "#include <stdio.h>\nint main(){int n;scanf(\"%d\",&n);if(n%2==0)printf(\"Even\");else printf(\"Odd\");return 0;}",
      selectedClass: "10th",
      subject: "Computer",
      selectedUnit: "Unit 3",
    ),

    Question(
      questionText: "What is the difference between relational and logical operators?",
      answer: "Relational operators compare two values, while logical operators combine multiple conditions.",
      selectedClass: "10th",
      subject: "Computer",
      selectedUnit: "Unit 3",
    ),

    Question(
      questionText: "Write a program to find the largest of two numbers.",
      answer: "#include <stdio.h>\nint main(){int a,b;scanf(\"%d%d\",&a,&b);if(a>b)printf(\"%d\",a);else printf(\"%d\",b);return 0;}",
      selectedClass: "10th",
      subject: "Computer",
      selectedUnit: "Unit 3",
    ),

    Question(
      questionText: "What is the use of else if ladder?",
      answer: "It is used when we have multiple conditions to check one by one.",
      selectedClass: "10th",
      subject: "Computer",
      selectedUnit: "Unit 3",
    ),

    Question(
      questionText: "Write a program to check whether a number is negative, zero, or positive.",
      answer: "#include <stdio.h>\nint main(){int n;scanf(\"%d\",&n);if(n>0)printf(\"Positive\");else if(n<0)printf(\"Negative\");else printf(\"Zero\");return 0;}",
      selectedClass: "10th",
      subject: "Computer",
      selectedUnit: "Unit 3",
    ),

    Question(
      questionText: "Which operator is used to combine two conditions?",
      answer: "Logical operators (&&, ||).",
      selectedClass: "10th",
      subject: "Computer",
      selectedUnit: "Unit 3",
    ),

    Question(
      questionText: "Give an example of nested if.",
      answer: "if(a>0){ if(a%2==0) printf(\"Positive Even\"); }",
      selectedClass: "10th",
      subject: "Computer",
      selectedUnit: "Unit 3",
    ),

    Question(
      questionText: "What will be the output of if(5>3) printf(\"Yes\");?",
      answer: "Yes",
      selectedClass: "10th",
      subject: "Computer",
      selectedUnit: "Unit 3",
    ),
  ],
  "Unit 4":[
    //MCQS
    Question(
      questionText: "Which loop is entry controlled?",
      options: ["while", "do…while", "for", "switch"],
      correctAnswer: "while",
      selectedClass: "10th",
      subject: "Computer",
      selectedUnit: "Unit 4",
    ),

    Question(
      questionText: "Which loop is exit controlled?",
      options: ["while", "do…while", "for", "if"],
      correctAnswer: "do…while",
      selectedClass: "10th",
      subject: "Computer",
      selectedUnit: "Unit 4",
    ),

    Question(
      questionText: "Which loop is best for known iterations?",
      options: ["while", "do…while", "for", "goto"],
      correctAnswer: "for",
      selectedClass: "10th",
      subject: "Computer",
      selectedUnit: "Unit 4",
    ),

    Question(
      questionText: "What will be the output of for(int i=1;i<=3;i++) printf(\"%d\",i);?",
      options: ["123", "321", "Error", "111"],
      correctAnswer: "123",
      selectedClass: "10th",
      subject: "Computer",
      selectedUnit: "Unit 4",
    ),

    Question(
      questionText: "Which loop executes body at least once?",
      options: ["while", "do…while", "for", "none"],
      correctAnswer: "do…while",
      selectedClass: "10th",
      subject: "Computer",
      selectedUnit: "Unit 4",
    ),

    Question(
      questionText: "Which keyword is used to exit a loop?",
      options: ["stop", "end", "break", "exit"],
      correctAnswer: "break",
      selectedClass: "10th",
      subject: "Computer",
      selectedUnit: "Unit 4",
    ),

    Question(
      questionText: "Which keyword is used to skip an iteration of loop?",
      options: ["end", "continue", "skip", "next"],
      correctAnswer: "continue",
      selectedClass: "10th",
      subject: "Computer",
      selectedUnit: "Unit 4",
    ),

    Question(
      questionText: "What is the output of while(0){printf(\"Yes\");}?",
      options: ["Yes", "No output", "Error", "Infinite Yes"],
      correctAnswer: "No output",
      selectedClass: "10th",
      subject: "Computer",
      selectedUnit: "Unit 4",
    ),

    Question(
      questionText: "What is the output of do{printf(\"Hi\");}while(0);?",
      options: ["Hi", "No output", "Error", "Infinite Hi"],
      correctAnswer: "Hi",
      selectedClass: "10th",
      subject: "Computer",
      selectedUnit: "Unit 4",
    ),

    //Short Questions
    Question(
      questionText: "What is a loop in C?",
      answer: "A loop is a control structure that repeats a block of statements until a condition is satisfied.",
      selectedClass: "10th",
      subject: "Computer",
      selectedUnit: "Unit 4",
    ),

    Question(
      questionText: "Why do we use loops in programming?",
      answer: "Loops are used to reduce repetition of code and make programs shorter and easier to manage.",
      selectedClass: "10th",
      subject: "Computer",
      selectedUnit: "Unit 4",
    ),

    Question(
      questionText: "Name the three types of loops in C.",
      answer: "while, do…while, and for loop.",
      selectedClass: "10th",
      subject: "Computer",
      selectedUnit: "Unit 4",
    ),

    Question(
      questionText: "Which loop checks the condition before executing?",
      answer: "while loop.",
      selectedClass: "10th",
      subject: "Computer",
      selectedUnit: "Unit 4",
    ),

    Question(
      questionText: "Which loop executes at least once even if the condition is false?",
      answer: "do…while loop.",
      selectedClass: "10th",
      subject: "Computer",
      selectedUnit: "Unit 4",
    ),

    Question(
      questionText: "Write the general syntax of while loop.",
      answer: "while(condition){\n   //statements\n}",
      selectedClass: "10th",
      subject: "Computer",
      selectedUnit: "Unit 4",
    ),

    Question(
      questionText: "Write the general syntax of do…while loop.",
      answer: "do{\n   //statements\n}while(condition);",
      selectedClass: "10th",
      subject: "Computer",
      selectedUnit: "Unit 4",
    ),

    Question(
      questionText: "Write the general syntax of for loop.",
      answer: "for(initialization; condition; increment){\n   //statements\n}",
      selectedClass: "10th",
      subject: "Computer",
      selectedUnit: "Unit 4",
    ),

    Question(
      questionText: "What is an infinite loop?",
      answer: "A loop that never ends because its condition always remains true.",
      selectedClass: "10th",
      subject: "Computer",
      selectedUnit: "Unit 4",
    ),

    Question(
      questionText: "Which loop is best when the number of iterations is known?",
      answer: "for loop.",
      selectedClass: "10th",
      subject: "Computer",
      selectedUnit: "Unit 4",
    ),

    Question(
      questionText: "Write a program to print first 10 natural numbers using for loop.",
      answer: "#include <stdio.h>\nint main(){int i;for(i=1;i<=10;i++)printf(\"%d \",i);return 0;}",
      selectedClass: "10th",
      subject: "Computer",
      selectedUnit: "Unit 4",
    ),

    Question(
      questionText: "Write a program to print table of 5 using while loop.",
      answer: "#include <stdio.h>\nint main(){int i=1;while(i<=10){printf(\"%d\\n\",5*i);i++;}return 0;}",
      selectedClass: "10th",
      subject: "Computer",
      selectedUnit: "Unit 4",
    ),

    Question(
      questionText: "Write a program to calculate factorial of a number using for loop.",
      answer: "#include <stdio.h>\nint main(){int n,f=1,i;scanf(\"%d\",&n);for(i=1;i<=n;i++)f*=i;printf(\"%d\",f);return 0;}",
      selectedClass: "10th",
      subject: "Computer",
      selectedUnit: "Unit 4",
    ),

    Question(
      questionText: "Which loop executes faster in C?",
      answer: "for loop (in most cases).",
      selectedClass: "10th",
      subject: "Computer",
      selectedUnit: "Unit 4",
    ),

    Question(
      questionText: "What is the difference between while and do…while?",
      answer: "while checks condition before executing, do…while executes at least once.",
      selectedClass: "10th",
      subject: "Computer",
      selectedUnit: "Unit 4",
    ),

    Question(
      questionText: "Write a program to print sum of first 10 numbers using while loop.",
      answer: "#include <stdio.h>\nint main(){int i=1,sum=0;while(i<=10){sum+=i;i++;}printf(\"%d\",sum);return 0;}",
      selectedClass: "10th",
      subject: "Computer",
      selectedUnit: "Unit 4",
    ),

  ],
  "Unit 5": [
    //MCQs
    Question(
      questionText: "Which function is used to print output in C?",
      options: ["cin", "cout", "printf", "print"],
      correctAnswer: "printf",
      selectedClass: "10th",
      subject: "Computer",
      selectedUnit: "Unit 5",
    ),

    Question(
      questionText: "Which function is used to take input in C?",
      options: ["scanf", "cin", "input", "read"],
      correctAnswer: "scanf",
      selectedClass: "10th",
      subject: "Computer",
      selectedUnit: "Unit 5",
    ),

    Question(
      questionText: "What is the return type of main() in C?",
      options: ["int", "void", "float", "char"],
      correctAnswer: "int",
      selectedClass: "10th",
      subject: "Computer",
      selectedUnit: "Unit 5",
    ),

    Question(
      questionText: "Which keyword is used to define a function that does not return a value?",
      options: ["null", "void", "empty", "none"],
      correctAnswer: "void",
      selectedClass: "10th",
      subject: "Computer",
      selectedUnit: "Unit 5",
    ),

    Question(
      questionText: "What is the correct function prototype for int add(int a, int b)?",
      options: ["int add(a,b);", "add(int,int);", "int add(int,int);", "function add(int,int);"],
      correctAnswer: "int add(int,int);",
      selectedClass: "10th",
      subject: "Computer",
      selectedUnit: "Unit 5",
    ),

    Question(
      questionText: "Which function returns the largest integer less than or equal to x?",
      options: ["ceil()", "round()", "floor()", "max()"],
      correctAnswer: "floor()",
      selectedClass: "10th",
      subject: "Computer",
      selectedUnit: "Unit 5",
    ),

    Question(
      questionText: "Which function is used to find power in C?",
      options: ["pow()", "power()", "exp()", "sqrt()"],
      correctAnswer: "pow()",
      selectedClass: "10th",
      subject: "Computer",
      selectedUnit: "Unit 5",
    ),

    Question(
      questionText: "Which function returns square root of a number?",
      options: ["sqrt()", "pow()", "root()", "abs()"],
      correctAnswer: "sqrt()",
      selectedClass: "10th",
      subject: "Computer",
      selectedUnit: "Unit 5",
    ),

    Question(
      questionText: "Which header file is required for mathematical functions?",
      options: ["math.h", "stdio.h", "conio.h", "string.h"],
      correctAnswer: "math.h",
      selectedClass: "10th",
      subject: "Computer",
      selectedUnit: "Unit 5",
    ),

    Question(
      questionText: "Which keyword is used to return a value from a function?",
      options: ["exit", "break", "return", "end"],
      correctAnswer: "return",
      selectedClass: "10th",
      subject: "Computer",
      selectedUnit: "Unit 5",
    ),
    //Short Questions
    Question(
      questionText: "What is a function in C?",
      answer: "A function is a block of statements that performs a specific task.",
      selectedClass: "10th",
      subject: "Computer",
      selectedUnit: "Unit 5",
    ),

    Question(
      questionText: "Name the two main types of functions in C.",
      answer: "Built-in functions and user-defined functions.",
      selectedClass: "10th",
      subject: "Computer",
      selectedUnit: "Unit 5",
    ),

    Question(
      questionText: "Give an example of a built-in function in C.",
      answer: "printf() and scanf().",
      selectedClass: "10th",
      subject: "Computer",
      selectedUnit: "Unit 5",
    ),

    Question(
      questionText: "Why are functions used in programming?",
      answer: "They improve reusability, readability, and modularity of code.",
      selectedClass: "10th",
      subject: "Computer",
      selectedUnit: "Unit 5",
    ),

    Question(
      questionText: "What is the syntax of function definition?",
      answer: "return_type function_name(parameters){\n   // body\n}",
      selectedClass: "10th",
      subject: "Computer",
      selectedUnit: "Unit 5",
    ),

    Question(
      questionText: "What is the difference between function declaration and definition?",
      answer: "Declaration specifies the function prototype, definition contains the actual code.",
      selectedClass: "10th",
      subject: "Computer",
      selectedUnit: "Unit 5",
    ),

    Question(
      questionText: "What is the purpose of return statement in C?",
      answer: "It is used to return a value from a function to the calling function.",
      selectedClass: "10th",
      subject: "Computer",
      selectedUnit: "Unit 5",
    ),

    Question(
      questionText: "Can a function return multiple values?",
      answer: "No, a function can return only one value at a time.",
      selectedClass: "10th",
      subject: "Computer",
      selectedUnit: "Unit 5",
    ),

    Question(
      questionText: "Write the general form of a function call.",
      answer: "function_name(arguments);",
      selectedClass: "10th",
      subject: "Computer",
      selectedUnit: "Unit 5",
    ),

    Question(
      questionText: "What is meant by arguments of a function?",
      answer: "Values or variables passed to a function during the call.",
      selectedClass: "10th",
      subject: "Computer",
      selectedUnit: "Unit 5",
    ),

    Question(
      questionText: "What are actual parameters?",
      answer: "The values or variables given in the function call.",
      selectedClass: "10th",
      subject: "Computer",
      selectedUnit: "Unit 5",
    ),

    Question(
      questionText: "What are formal parameters?",
      answer: "The variables defined in the function definition to receive values.",
      selectedClass: "10th",
      subject: "Computer",
      selectedUnit: "Unit 5",
    ),

    Question(
      questionText: "Write a program to find the square of a number using function.",
      answer: "#include <stdio.h>\nint square(int n){return n*n;}\nint main(){int n;scanf(\"%d\",&n);printf(\"%d\",square(n));}",
      selectedClass: "10th",
      subject: "Computer",
      selectedUnit: "Unit 5",
    ),

    Question(
      questionText: "Write a program to calculate factorial using function.",
      answer: "#include <stdio.h>\nint fact(int n){int f=1,i;for(i=1;i<=n;i++)f*=i;return f;}\nint main(){int n;scanf(\"%d\",&n);printf(\"%d\",fact(n));}",
      selectedClass: "10th",
      subject: "Computer",
      selectedUnit: "Unit 5",
    ),

    Question(
      questionText: "What is the difference between void and int function?",
      answer: "A void function does not return a value, an int function returns an integer value.",
      selectedClass: "10th",
      subject: "Computer",
      selectedUnit: "Unit 5",
    ),

    Question(
      questionText: "Can we define a function inside another function in C?",
      answer: "No, nested function definitions are not allowed in standard C.",
      selectedClass: "10th",
      subject: "Computer",
      selectedUnit: "Unit 5",
    ),

    Question(
      questionText: "What is recursion?",
      answer: "A process in which a function calls itself.",
      selectedClass: "10th",
      subject: "Computer",
      selectedUnit: "Unit 5",
    ),

    Question(
      questionText: "Give one example of recursive function.",
      answer: "Factorial function using recursion.",
      selectedClass: "10th",
      subject: "Computer",
      selectedUnit: "Unit 5",
    ),
  ]

};
